# Ernita Dewi Puspitasari

ernita.dewi91@gmail.com +6281380260279 Jakarta, Indonesia December 23, 2020

## Summary

Accounting manager in financial technology industry with solid experience as auditor. Skilled in planned and prepared financial statements in accordance with financial accounting standards and international audit standards, as well as in dealing with Indonesia's taxation regulation. With a can do attitude, I always accept new challenge, adapt quickly, and strive to give real impact to the organization.

## Work Experience

Payfazz

Accounting Manager

Jakarta, Indonesia
November 2019 - Present

- Handle financial reporting of 3 companies in Fazz Financial Group.
- Evaluate efficiency and effectiveness of accounting processes, and make recommendations to optimize them.
- Prepare and analyze financial statement in monthly basis.
- Design and implement automated journal entry for new product by collaborating with product team as well as financial engineer.
- Analyze the impact of foreign operations on reported financial results, including foreign exchange transactions.
- Ensure integrity, accuracy, and completeness of financial statements by discussing the need for and nature of appropriate disclosures.

#### PricewaterhouseCoopers

Jakarta, Indonesia

Senior Associate Auditor

August 2019 - November 2019

- Similar responsibility with what I had done previously in PwC but with a bigger client allocation.

Freelance
Accountant
Stockholm, Sweden
July 2018 - September 2018

Prepared statements of financial position and income statement of profit and loss for the client.

### PricewaterhouseCoopers

Jakarta, Indonesia

Senior Associate Auditor

June 2013 - January 2017

- Planned audit procedures that allign with auditing standard and PSAK as well as prepared the budgets and resources to ensure the audit would go smoothly.
- Coordinated the team and its audit assignments to ensure that the team was aware of clients' business processes and current relevant issues that might impact their audit procedures.
- Identified and assessed risk of material misstatements of financial statements due to fraud, and assessed internal control (if necessary) to ensure the control is effective.
- Designed and implemented responses to material misstatement including performed and tested the appropriateness of journal entry testing.
- Communicated audits findings to the manager and the clients effectively.

Deloitte Jakarta, Indonesia

Junior Auditor January 2013 - May 2013

Responsible in doing financial audits in a particular area such as cash and cash equivalent, account
payable, advance and pre-payment, property plant and equipment, and general and administrative
expenses.

### **Education**

#### Universitas Indonesia

Jakarta, Indonesia

Bachelor of Economics, Accounting

Agustus 2009 - February 2013

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude with a Bachelor of Economics degree in 3.5 years.
- Assisted a number of lectures including principal accounting, quantitative method in business, and investment management.
- Extracurricular: Financial controller in the Student Executive Board (BEM UI) with the responsibility
  to manage and keep track of monthly budget for all departments as well as to report financial statements
  of the organization.

### **Skills**

- Financial audit and accounting.
- Analyzing income and deferred tax calculation.
- Working with numbers and analyzing statistical and financial data.
- Analyzing financial statements and draft reports.
- Expert in Microsoft Excel and fast learner in using any financial software on demand.
- Managing a team in terms of resources allocation, budgeting, and time management.
- Experience in using SAP System.